Guide to the OutRight Records, 1983-1995 RL.00984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
OutRight records
1983-1995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
OutRight (Durham, N.C.)
RL.00984
5.25 Linear Feet
OutRight is a Triangle-area organization that was founded in 1990 and is now disbanded. OutRight provided support for gay youth and other young people with questions about their sexual orientation. The OutRight records consist of meeting minutes, correspondence, financial records, resources and programs (including clippings, flyers, and pamphlets), and literature on AIDS and sexuality. The materials also include reports on nationwide trends and LGBTQ issues.
Access Restrictions
Collection contains sensitive information. Contact Research Services for Access: https://duke.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_8fblaT2NbgbQujj
Provenance
The OutRight Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1997-2009.
Historical Note
OutRight was a Triangle-area organization founded in 1990 and now disbanded. OutRight provided support for gay youth and other young people with questions about their sexual orientation.
Collection Overview
The OutRight Records chiefly consist of minutes from meetings, correspondence, financial records, publicity (including clippings, flyers, and pamphlets), and literature on AIDS and sexuality. Also included are reports on nationwide trends and LGBTQ issues, the organization's by-laws, fundraising, correspondence, program planning, and administrative information.
Durham (N.C.) -- Social conditions; Coming out (sexual orientation); Gay activists -- North Carolina; Safe sex in AIDS prevention; AIDS (Disease) in adolescence -- Prevention; Bisexuality; Teenagers -- Sexual behavior -- United States; Gay teenagers; Lesbianism; Gay lesbians; Homosexuality and education; Homosexuality -- United States; OutRight (Durham, N.C.); Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Administrative Materials, 1986-1995; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Administrative Materials relate mostly to office files, such as by-laws and policies for the organization, fundraising, events, grant opportunities and applications, and general donation information. Materials are arranged chronologically by year and alphabetically within each year.
  - 501(c) 3 blank, 1986-1991 (Box 1)
  - Articles: Outright, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Blank stationary and notes, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Board meeting propsals, 1990s (Box 1)
  - By-laws other organizations, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Calendars and events, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Fax and telephone, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Fundraising committee, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Ground rules for Outright youth meetings, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Lease/rent, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Mailing labels, 1990s (Box 11)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Personal information restricted until 2074
  - Mailing list, 1990s (Box 11)
  - Manuals, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Minority section notes, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Mission Statement, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Notebook #1 "Calendar of Events" "Work Records", 1990s (Box 1)
  - Notes, volunteering, Outright 101, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - Outright directions and office hours, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Outright organization information, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - Outright 101, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Policies for adults working with youth, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Receipts for conferences, programs, and resources, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Start-up packet of by-laws, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Statutes, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Tax ID number - LGHP, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Z. Smith Reynolds Foundation, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Articles of Incorportation, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1991 September 03 (Box 1)
  - Christmas fundraising letters, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
  - Formation of Outright, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Grant applications, 1991-1994 (Box 2)
  - Grant opportunities, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Major campaign review board, 1991 April 24 (Box 2)
  - Outright policies and by-laws, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Bryan Foundation, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Fundraising letters, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Notebook #1: Youth meeting summary sheet, 1993; 2 folders (Box 11)
    Personal information restricted until 2068
  - Notebook #2: Working files, 1993-1995; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Notebook #1 Adolescence: Sexual Orientation..., 1993 (Box 2)
  - Notebook #1 Outright Facilitator schedules, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Outright by-laws, position descriptions, and applications, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Outright contributions, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Southern Community Partners, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Blank fundraising lettes, 1994 December 17 (Box 3)
  - By-laws amendments, 1994 (Box 3)
  - By-laws, organization info, letters, and referrals, 1994 (Box 3)
  - By-laws Outright, 1994 (Box 3)
  - By-laws proposed changes and amendments, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Facilitators schedules (old-current), 1994 (Box 3)
  - Grant opportunities - Southern Partners, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Non-profit status, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Outright treasurer's reports, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - To Do, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Blank monthly calendars, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Fundraising and donations, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Invoices, brochures, and other youth services, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Outright mailing data, 1995 (Box 11)
    Personal information restricted until 2070
- Minutes, 1990-1994; 2
  Minutes include the minutes of program committee meetings and retreat meetings. Materials are arranged chronologically by year.
  - Notebook: Outright Minutes, 1990-1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Retreat minutes, 1991 October (Box 4)
  - Outright program committee meeting minutes, 1991 December 10 (Box 4)
- Programs and Resources, 1983-1995; 3
  Programs and resources include pamphlets, flyers, and literature of other LGBTQ youth groups, articles written about the OutRight organization and about LGBTQ communities, and national reports about violence against the LGBTQ communities. Materials also include OutRight's programs, such as the hotline call logs, flyers, resource lists, and local events. Materials are arranged chronologically by year and alphabetically within each year.
  - Bibliographies, 1983-1989 (Box 4)
  - Parents magazine, 1984-1992 (Box 4)
  - Brochures and articles, 1988-1994 (Box 4)
  - Brochures, newsletters, and flyers, 1988-1995 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous articles and flyers and questionnaire, 1988-1994 (Box 4)
  - Print guides, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Project 10 handbook, 1988 July 07 (Box 4)
  - "Bridges of Respect", 1989 July (Box 4)
  - "Being Lesbian" by Lorraine Trenchard, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Report of the secretary's task force on Youth Suicide, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Youth Services Clearninghouse Orange County, 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - Article: "Parents protest gay button fight at school", 1990s (Box 4)
  - Brochures, 1990-1994 (Box 4)
  - Brochures (Outright) Masters, 1990s (Box 4)
  - "Disclosing homosexuality leads teen to gay rights fight", 1990 August 13 (Box 4)
  - Episcopal Diocese of NC, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
  - Formation of sexual minority youth groups, 1990s (Box 5)
  - Friends For Life flyer (Larry and Jim), 1990s (Box 5)
  - Hotline Logs, 1990-1994; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Lesbians: Mademoiselle "Women in love" article, 1990s (Box 5)
  - Masters, 1990s (Box 5)
  - National reports, 1990 (Box 5)
  - National youth groups, 1990s (Box 5)
  - Notebook, 1990s (Box 5)
  - "Outright focuses on life as a gay teen", 1990 April 01 (Box 5)
  - Outright papers, 1990s (Box 5)
  - Pen pals, 1990s (Box 5)
  - Photographs, 1990s (Box 5)
  - PSA's, 1990s (Box 5)
  - Speaker's Bureau - Outright, 1990s (Box 5)
  - Speaking engagements, 1990 (Box 5)
  - "Talking Outright", 1990 (Box 6)
  - Transgender, 1990s (Box 6)
  - Unitarian Universalist Social Concerns Grant Panel, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Wake Co. Human Svc. Agencies, 1990s (Box 6)
  - "A Reading List for Gay Men", 1991 January (Box 6)
  - "Beyond Rhetoric: A New American Agenda for Children and Families", 1991 (Box 6)
  - Booklets, 1991-1995 (Box 6)
  - Greater Triangle Community Foundation, 1991-1993 (Box 6)
  - "Growing up gay" article, 1991 August 25 (Box 6)
  - Harvey Milk H.S. article, 1991 October 13 (Box 6)
  - Jordan H.S. article, 1991 November (Box 6)
  - Newsletters and reports, 1991-1994 (Box 6)
  - Referrals list, 1991 (Box 6)
  - "Adolescent Health Promotion", 1992 May 01 (Box 6)
  - Brochures and reports, 1992-1995 (Box 6)
  - Chapel Hill H.S. articles and reprints, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Chicago Resource Center, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - "Moving Beyond Binary Thinking", 1992 (Box 7)
  - Riverside H.S. article and reprints, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - "Young and Gray" article, 1992 April 04 (Box 7)
  - Articles, letters, brochures, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - ASPYN, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Directories and reports on the violence and discrimination against lesbians and gays, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
  - For Better or Worse, 1993 (Box 7)
  - NC State report on HIV, 1993 May 10 (Box 7)
  - Other groups and programs, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Outright libraries, 1993 October (Box 7)
  - Reports about Code Blue and homophobia, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Reports about violence against gays and lesbians, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Articles, brochures, and reports, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Articles: Other youth groups, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Education specific, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Juvenile mentoring program, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous articles and flyers, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Newist, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Newsletter suggestions, 1994 September (Box 8)
  - Outright forms, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Outreach, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Prom idea, 1994 May 28 (Box 8)
  - Retreat locations, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Smart Sex, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Surveys and flyers, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Video information, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Workshop notes and papers, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Bisexual resource list, 1995 May 20 (Box 8)
  - Hot Pink Notebook, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Letters from National Lesbian and Gay Health Conference, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Man Bites Dog LtRS, 1995 (Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1990-1995, 1998; 4
  Correspondence includes letters between staff members, about National Coming Out Day, youth programs, and donations and contributions. Materials are arranged chronologically by year and alphabetically within each year.
  - Fiss correspondences, 1990-1994 (Box 8)
  - Donation letters, receipts, 1991-1995 (Box 11)
  - Mail/letters received, 1991-1995 (Box 9)
  - Stonewall dinner, 1991 April 01 (Box 9)
  - Correspondences, 1992-1994 (Box 9)
  - H.S. newspaper ad correspondences, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Bo correspondences, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Alan Teasley to Tracy Mitchel, 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - National Coming Out Day, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Outright to Time Out, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Ricoh and Uni-copy letters, 1994 (Box 9)
  - USPS, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Contribution letter from Lee and Wells, 1995 June 12 (Box 9)
  - Letters from Ricky Claggett, 1995 May 25 (Box 9)
  - Youth letters, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Letter from Darryl, 1998 December 20 (Box 9)
- Volunteering and Board Members, 1990-1995; 5
  Volunteering and board members materials relate mostly to information about OutRight staff and volunteers, such as volunteering opportunities, training packets, list of volunteers and board members, and applications. Materials are arranged chronologically by year and alphabetically within each year.
  - Advisory Board, 1990s (Box 9)
  - Blank volunteer applications, 1990s (Box 9)
  - Board members and facilitators, 1990s (Box 9)
  - Board/volunteer list, 1990s (Box 9)
  - List, 1990s (Box 9)
  - Outright volunteer opportunities, 1990s (Box 9)
  - Phone/address list, 1990s (Box 9)
  - Volunteer training packet, 1990s (Box 9)
  - Volunteer applications - Outright and LGHP, 1990s (Box 9)
  - Non-active volunteers, 1991-1994 (Box 9)
  - Notebook #1: Volunteer application/information, 1994; 2 folders (Box 11)
    Personal information restricted until 2069
  - Volunteering announcements, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Volunteers on leave of abscence, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Volunteering training list, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Board members - leave/resigned, 1995 January (Box 10)
  - Current volunteer applications, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Lori Wolf and youth, 1995 June 27 (Box 10)